[Music]
let's explore let's learn let's
collaborate let's come together at Cisco
live 2024 Amsterdam let's
[Music]
go we are really thrilled to have all of
you with us for this exciting event
filled with Innovation and collaboration
and Cutting Edge technology over the
next few days you are going to have the
opportunity to engage with industry
leaders and to explore all the latest
advancements in networking and to
connect with like-minded
professionals so whether you're a
seasoned expert or just starting your
journey Cisco live is the place to be
get ready for an immersive experience
inspiring key notes Hands-On laps
thought-provoking Innovation talks and
Illuminating interviews all right guys
well of course don't miss the world of
solutions we've got everything you need
to know about networking the latest
advancements and collaboration not to
mention deep Dives on iot as well as oh
my gosh data analytics and of course
artificial
intelligence at the Cisco showcase
explore Cisco's latest products and
solutions engage in live demos and don't
miss out on the interactive networking
Cloud Solutions War the meeting Village
this is where the most creative
individuals get together to network to
share and to figure out what to do next
they're having meetings in the meeting
Village and here at the Innovation
theater we'll hear more about use cases
success stories thought leadership and
we'll explore the latest and greatest
strengths in the technology industry now
here in the hub we have got Tech teams
and networking professionals we have it
leaders literally thousands of people
who are all making their way right here
to share their ideas and to talk through
challenges and even to engage in a
little friendly competition with one
another now while you're here in the hub
you can explore Cisco solutions for
hybrid work and for smart buildings
sustainability AI you can connect with
Cisco enthusiasts at Cisco Insider you
can learn about the latest in security
at Security Central and you can shop
we've got the latest merchandise and
exclusive Cisco live products right over
there in the amazing Cisco
store and of course the Keynotes we'll
hear from Cisco's leaders on how we are
embracing AI powered capabilities well
throughout the conference we'll be
joined by multiple Cisco top experts
right here in the Cisco TV studios we
want to know what it means for you to be
at Cisco live so join the conversation
using your favorite social media channel
using the hashtag Cisco live Amia and
tune in to cisco.com for the full
enhanced being experience join us for 3
Days of inspiration learning and fun
welcome to Cisco live 2024 in Amsterdam
let's go
and welcome everyone we are delighted to
have you here on the live stream this is
this exciting moment when this all kicks
off here in Amsterdam at Cisco live 2024
we are thrilled wherever you happen to
be joining us from all around the world
welcome in and welcome to your event
this really is all about you and we're
absolutely delighted my name is Steve
molter I am one of four of your hosts
you will get to know all of us very well
over the next few days and I'm joined
here on the set by my friend Cedric
nalder hello Cedric Steve which is
basically Dutch for good you are so good
right away right out of the gate I love
that I love it too it's it's great to be
back here in Amsterdam like you know
it's it's just awesome to be here with
you again Steve I I missed you buddy
well thank you my friend I appreciate
that it's hard to believe that it's
already been a year and last year I had
no voice so this year we're all here
together and the voice is strong and I'm
feeling good about it let's talk about
what we're headed into right now at this
moment we're just under 30 minutes away
from our opening keynote uh kicking off
at 9:30 a.m. Central European Time I am
so excited for this and all of you can
stay right here with us on the live
stream right up to the first word and
through the last Oliver Tuk is with us
Jonathan Davidson G2 Patel along with
run Desai um Adel tretta Fletcher prevan
we've got an All-Star team here and
Cedric I'm really excited because we're
going to hear all the different ways
that we can access infinite
possibilities by harnessing the power of
AI and we are going to hear so much
about gen AI over the course of the week
here Oliver Tusk president of Cisco emia
along with Cisco technology leaders
they're going to really unpack our
gamechanging technology announcements
and Innovations they will unveil all of
the great Cisco solutions that are brand
new they'll demonstrate our commitment
here at Cisco to creating a unified
experience for our customers using Aid
driven capabilities and again we're
going to bring you every word of it it's
going to start just under 30 minutes
from right now so don't go away now as I
mentioned Cedric we are two of the hosts
yep we have two other hosts on the live
stream all week long and we're going to
meet them right now we're going to head
out to the keynote space Rob Boyd and
Nish Parker out there Rob Nish hello my
friends hello hello hello I am so happy
to be back here working with Nish again
we are pausing to get our pictures taken
from the SLR camera over here I think
those are the ones that that get placed
in the uh the postevent keynote uh
PowerPoint if you will afterwards guys
the energy in here is incredible yes the
big thing that jumps out for me this
year it's the same location that we were
in before the music is still loud the
base still travels all the way through
you and you're in the room which is
fantastic I don't know if you can see
this Steve but we've got lasers lots of
really nice lasers I think they're going
to do something special with it have you
been able to pick up on any of that I
have I mean it the energy as you said is
amazing in here I want to kind of play
that game you know you avoid the lasers
and you climb over them and then under
them like some kind of mission type of
theme um but the music in here it's
really tense it's getting people excited
for the keynote what are you most
excited about this week Rob just one
thing one thing what the heck are we
doing with AI I feel like we don't hear
enough about Ai and what everybody's
doing with it I think it's time I'm just
going to make the call here right now we
need to speak up we need to quit
sweeping this under the rug and we need
to share what it is we're doing with
those two letters yes for sure yeah 100%
I'm excited to hear Ai and bet you
anything it's going to be mentioned in
the Keynote you and I can play AI Bingo
they will know that we've been heard
exactly but I know through the week as
well there's going to be so many guests
joining us in the studio we're going to
be out in the world of solutions and
we're going to show how AI is actually
coming to life and how customers are
using it and a cost effective safe um an
ethical way right yep absolutely in just
a moment she's going to go run and find
some people to talk to I think you got
some Executives lined up I'm going to go
try and dig out some Cisco Champions
these are all my friends that basically
hold me up behind the scenes with
knowledge and just an understanding of
everything outside of Cisco so we're
going to bring all that to you in just a
moment so Steve let's go back to you in
the studio Rob thank you so much I love
that you going to track down the uh the
Champions and some of the executives you
are our eyes and ears out there on the
keynote floor bringing it all to us you
can see that we have not opened up the
shows space here on the exhibit floor
the world of solutions will open up as
soon as the keynote comes to a close and
we'll be bringing it all to you live
right from here in the studio um Cedric
we are together we're here in this
amazing space and this amazing show to
gain knowledge to explore
possibilities Cisco as we just heard
we're harnessing these AI capabilities
to help us succeed in technological
transformation and transformation I
think is such a core part of what we do
that is what this event is about how do
we improve how do we grow the
capabilities of what people are doing
right absolutely yeah um let's talk
social media for a moment because we've
got all these folks watching us joining
us from all over the world how do they
stay in contact with us and how do we
stay in contact with them absolutely
it's a it's a two-way street for us
right like we show you what's going on
here but also you need to let us know
how you're feeling about the event right
so first of all we're on cisco.com Cisco
live and Cisco soci social media
channels um where you can just tune in
and understand like what we're doing
here and fun fact Steve actually re
rolling 24/7 on Cisco life.com um there
are subtitles in seven languages and you
can send us some emojis if you want to
and I'm very interested Steve what is
your favorite emoji my favorite emo
actually my favorite emoji is the ey
roll Emoji it's the one that I seem to
use most in texts and and Facebook I
don't know if that makes me ironic or
what that is but uh yeah that's one that
I click all the time especially when I
see something that just baffles me it's
always I roll Emoji although I do love
the laughing with the tears coming down
what is that actually called you're
younger than I am you would know these
things the laughing crying Emoji sure
we'll call it the laughing crying Emoji
that's perfect all right so as people
reach out to us the social media area
have you had a chance to head over into
the social media Zone and talk to the
folks who are back there what did you
see when you were over on that side so
we have a whole team here of our social
media team that will interact with you
on our social media channels as well so
as I said let us know how you're feeling
send us your thoughts your pictures
whatever you want to send us and use #
Cisco life Andia I'll say that again
it's underneath me as well right now but
hash Cisco live and Mia Steve and I and
the whole crew will be watching out for
what you'll be sharing with us as well
that's absolutely right this event is
always about connection it's about human
beings coming together to create
remarkable things to uh create better
experiences to help digitization
capabilities so it's not just about
growing organizations and growing
companies it's how do we connect
together in Partnership and all week
long here in the studio in all of the ey
talks in the keynote today we're going
to hear it again again again and again
partnership partnership partnership
Cisco is not an island we are always
always always better when we work
together in Partnership and meeting
people and being together that's what
it's all about so Cedric before hang on
to that for a moment hang on to that for
just a moment I want to hear the idea
but I do want to go out to Rob because I
believe Rob has one of our Cisco
Champions with us right now I do Steve
thank you so much and actually what I
found was not a Cisco Champion although
I'm sure you're a champion very much so
just not officially in the program
perhaps but sergy you're telling me this
is not your first Cisco live but you
come here specifically on from the
learning perspective but tell us a
little bit about what you do first and
what brings you here what value do you
find in the event well I'm a network
engineer and a junior Network architect
and I do a lot of network designs and
Network troubleshooting so I like CIS
live because of a lot of technical
sessions that I can learn new stuff
especially about Network programmability
and Automation in which I'm very
interested so on the network programming
and automation are there any is there
anything specific that you're looking
for us to announce here or perhaps
questions you came in to to get some
better answers for why you've got access
to so many experts no it's uh general
knowledge mainly i' I've got no um
specific questions but usually Cisco
life is pretty packed with useful
information for everyone is there
expectations that you're supposed to
bring certain amounts of knowledge back
because you're the guy who got to go or
did more members of your team also get
to travel here yeah I've got my uh
manager here as well The Honorable
company he's here he's I've got him
interested in network automation as well
so he's attending a technical session at
the moment I'm kind of the most
proficient with network Automation in my
company at the moment but trying to
bring other guys on board and they're
very very uh passionate about it and
they very interested in so surely it's
very helpful to them as well that's very
good I'm always uh admiring those of us
who I think it's a necessity that we
have to really commit to lifelong
learning and it's a lot of very urgent
learning but Serge thank you so much for
joining us appreciate your time enjoy
the rest of the show and with that we'll
go back to Steve in the studio thank you
so much and give our thanks to Serge as
well it's great to hear his uh his views
on how he's enjoying the event so far I
cut you off a moment ago Cedric what
were you about to say because I think
this was an important idea you know I
think when you said that it's about
relationship building about elevating
people about coming together Cisco were
just really good I think in conting the
unconnected we hear it again and again
right it's such a big catchphrase for us
here at Cisco we hear it across the show
this is where the best and the brightest
Minds in I come together we just heard
it from Serge to learn to experience to
gain education and certification and
inspiration everything that's all around
us here right now in the world of
solutions and across the Hub it's all
tailor made for creativity and
digitization and Ai and security really
everything that an organization of any
size any organization including the ones
just like yours it's what you need to
thrive and to differentiate at speed and
at scale so Cedric I'm going to ask very
quickly while we get settled out here on
the keynote space you are mostly having
internal conversations with teams right
but those internal conversations in that
goto Market strategy concept within your
Cisco UK team you are hearing from
customers every single day about what it
is that they want from us what they want
us to do and I think that's reflected on
the show floor right absolutely I've
said it to you before Steve it's all
about ai ai ai right those are the two
letters that I think come up the most uh
we'll see lots of Innovations from our
collaboration team to all across our
portfolio how AI can elevate your
organization and how we can actually
make it more connected and how we can be
proactive with our technology uh to help
you there so I think AI is one uh the
other one I think is sustainability yeah
right I think it was our major team last
year but it's still present all over the
conference uh here as well and there is
a great sustainability boot that we will
visit uh later this week so I'm really
excited about that as well excellent and
I think our partners are heavily focused
on sustainability as well so I'm looking
out into the keynote space it's starting
to fill up and I believe Nish Parker has
found a friend hi Nish I have found a
friend thanks so much Steve I'm here
with Rodney Clark Rodney you are the SVP
of small medium business and
Partnerships a big big role how are you
doing today Nish I'm doing great today
this is so fantastic what a great
environment and great to be here amazing
thanks so much so you have been with
Cisco I think about 4 weeks you're brand
new um you're leading obviously our
partner small medium business
organization what are your impressions
so far what are you most excited about
I'm most excited about joining a company
that's a Leading Edge technology company
Leading Edge from our secure networking
to observability the fact that AI is
built within every single product in our
portfolio it's so great to be a part of
it and it's great to be here witnessing
it live at Cisco live today for sure and
I know we're going to hear a lot about
AI this week we already have mentioned
it a lot on the broadcast but you're
going to hear from our Executives in the
world of solutions it's going to be
throughout the show um now Rodney this
is your first time at Cisco live right
um so what surprised you what are you
going to be up to this week well this
week it's all about the customer Cisco
live is all about the customer and I'm
excited to see how our messages land
with our customers from our largest
Enterprise customers to those small and
medium Enterprises that do business with
us and rely on us every day to bring
value and deliver value got it and
obviously you know here at Cisco live
Cisco is really powerful in partnership
with the partner organizations that we
work with and I know yesterday we had a
very special day with our Cisco Partners
tell us a bit about that yeah we had
about a thousand of our partners come in
and I most people know Cisco is a
partner-led company we talk about how
important those partners are to us and
we talked about things Nish like AI that
you and I discussed just a second ago we
talked about our services platform and
how we enable them to deliver more
services to our customers and it was
also a great opportunity for them to
give us feedback on how they can better
service our customers so what a powerful
day as a small subset of Cisco live I
love that and obviously our partners are
an extension of the experience and how
they experience this go so I really love
that um so you know like we said
Partners do play a key role in bringing
value to our customers what do you want
our customers to know about our partner
ecosystem yeah our again Cisco is a
partner-led company partners are not an
extension of what we do they are Cisco
in essence and so when we bring our
value to a customer that is Cisco
capability along with our partner
capability we're really bringing the
best that the industry has to offer and
so we're going to continue to invest in
those Partners in those Partnerships so
that we can deliver that value to our
customers and again that's what I want
to hear about today at Cisco live is how
those two things come together and do
you know what source much Rodney is
Oliver TK who obviously was in your Ro
just before you four weeks ago is going
to be joining us on stage shortly um so
that's really great to see obviously you
know he's very excited about our
partners about small medium business I'm
sure he's going to take that message
through the week as well right truth be
told I'm going to sit right in the front
row and do a virtual high five with
Oliver as he's up there representing
Cisco I love that so have you walked
around the world Solutions when did you
arrive what have you seen so far I got
in what Monday Sunday morning 9:00 and
immediately came came into meetings with
our partners and with our customers
walked around the solution showcase and
oh my gosh just blown away as you
mentioned I'm 4 weeks in so I'm still
sponging and learning everything talk to
so many people around our Technologies
talk to so many customers who are
implementing it I'm I'm riding on a high
right now I'm pretty buzzed from the
excitement of all of it I still have
more meetings and more solution walks to
do before the end of the day so I'm let
let me add it Nish let me get at it I
love it well Rodney I'm going to let you
go and get on with all of that let's how
head back to the studio thank you so
much Rodney welcome we are so glad to
have you here with us Bravo Rodney well
done and he said it right there Cisco is
a partner-driven company right Cedric
absolutely and I think what he also said
is Cisco life is for you guys right for
customers for partners and I had a
chance to walk around yesterday and like
um basically talk to a few of our
attendees in the world of solutions and
they always come back and it's like
they're like super excited they're
looking forward to this event every
single year and it's a meeting hot spot
for them right we have this whole
content in part but also you bump into
Old Friends you build you bump into Old
colleagues you make new friends you talk
to Executives so it's it's also about
relationships Steve it's so much about
relationships I want to come back to the
technology for just a moment with you
sedric while we have a second and we're
setting up for our next segment over
here um we've already said it what four
times here AI we're going to hear it
again and again and again and again it
is about how it empowers people it's how
it empowers relationships why are we
such a leader here in the a I area and
what a lot of people don't know is that
Cisco has been engaging in the AI
Frontier for a long time now this is not
new we've been in the better part of
this you know for a decade at this point
so what we're talking about right now is
generative AI That's the buzz it is
actually part of a much larger movement
in artificial intelligence being driven
by data science and by Machine learning
and by human connection these are the
things that reached maturity a while ago
but for us here at Cisco we were in
early Builder an early investor an early
adopter in predictive AI we've seen it
for a while and we're seeing it out here
we've got AI all across the portfolio
WebEx uh worldclass audio and video and
language intelligence within WebEx
capabilities great AI noise filtering
cinematic Focus automatic language
transition if we look into Cisco
security products which we'll talk a ton
about this week they're enhanced with
Aid driven threat detection and anomaly
prediction capabilities they're making
the world safer for our customers so
we're moving AI into full stack
observability we're going to hear a lot
about that but again the whole idea is
how do we build organizations up and
what are organizations made of they made
of people it's a relationship People to
People thing so before we head back over
to you because I know you've got some
thoughts on that I actually want to go
back out to the show floor because in my
feed I can see that Nish has a very
special not just guest but a series of
guests with her hey Nish hey Steve yes
I've not got one guest I've not got two
guests I've got three three guests with
me today super special guests as well
may I add I'm here with Carrie Palin
Carrie you are our SVP and CMO how are
you doing doing great I literally landed
in the Netherlands about 3 hours ago and
I'm so excited to be here you look fresh
you look wrapped up for amdam it's a
little bit cold outside but we're going
to have a really great week here at the
Ry NES you are our VP of Amia marketing
how are you doing I'm good it's been so
exciting to be here the first day
yesterday was fantastic so yeah I'm
amazing amazing thanks much and finally
Britney bartett you are our VP of global
field marketing obviously including Amir
here in the region how are you doing I
am doing fantastic we've been on a
little Amia tour landed here in
Amsterdam kicked off yesterday it has
been absolutely incredible awesome so
Carrie I'm going to come to you first
what are you most excited about this
week I know you've been to several Cisco
lives what's different what's exciting
this year well there's a lot going on
this year but I'm really excited to
listen to our GMS this morning get into
where AI is permeating our entire
portfolio it's obviously the theme of
the year and sort of I get I think of
the next decade in Tech and so there's a
lot going on at Cisco that I can't wait
for our customers to hear and understand
but I also just excited to commune with
everyone here the audience the energy is
so palpable and I can't wait to sit down
and just hear what they have to say
thank you Karen Nas in contrast this is
uh your first ever sis go live right
what's it like to be here in the room as
a first timer it's amazing I am little
Blown Away by the magnitude and the
energy around it's been a fantastic day
yesterday and I can't wait to connect
with Partners customers and colleagues
thank you neis and Britney I know
obviously you lead all of our Global
field teams as I've said including Amia
so what are you excited about this week
what's different this year what are you
going to be up to this week well the
energy here is absolutely electric and
it's so great to see this many people I
know we have record attendance so that's
super exciting um and I'm just really
excited to get to spend more time with
our customers our partners and of course
with our colleagues here at Cisco too
awesome and Carrie I know this week we
are talking a lot about AI it's ai ai ai
we were saying we were going to play AI
Bingo this week but it's not just a
buzzword it's not just something we say
there's a lot of meaning to it around
you know we're going to hear that in the
Keynotes we'll hear it in the world of
solutions how is AI showing up at Cisco
life oh it's everywhere which is the
really exciting thing it isn't anecdotal
for us it's actually something we've
been into for many many years it's a our
portfolio in networking in observability
in security you'll see all of it this
week but also tease out a little bit
about the promise of AI with Splunk
potentially closing soon we hope and uh
that with the combination of Cisco is
pretty pretty thrilling exciting times
now this year the theme is let's go what
does let's go mean for you and I'll ask
for you to say one sentence what is
let's go what does it mean how are you
experiencing the
event well it for me it means that we
just absolutely hit it hard in the back
half of our fiscal year with our
partners and our customers and just get
it going thank you nees what does let's
go mean to me means let's go exploring
opportunities on how to work with
customer partners and the Cisco Team all
right and Brittney finally coming to you
let's go is what does it mean to you
well we were with a bunch of our
partners yesterday and so many of them
were talking about the opportunity ahead
and I think this is just the it is the
time to go capture that out with our
customers in the market got it and just
my final question for you obviously
we're here the keynote is about to begin
is there anyone you're particularly
excited to connect with any session
you're particularly excited to attend
any topic you want to discuss what's top
of mind for
you okay um I'm really looking forward
actually we have two sessions I'm
excited about one is a session with the
Netherlands Partners about sales and
marketing alignment um which I'm part of
the panel so I'm really looking forward
to that and then our whole inclusion
series is also fantastic I saw that
around the future program we've got lots
in the sustainability Zone as well well
thank you to all of you for joining me
here we're about to go into the keynote
but for now let's head back to the
studio thank you so much Nish what a
great job I appreciate it I'm so glad
you got those wonderful humans with you
thank you to Carrie to nevas to Britney
uh for giving us their feedback and neas
especially thank you for telling us what
let's go is all about what it actually
means I mean we see it here in The
Branding we see it all around us on the
show floor but it is that drive it's
that drive to create it's that drive to
connect it's that drive to digitize to
produce to elevate organizations right
Cedric yeah because if you think about
it Steve the technology landscape is
moving faster than ever yeah right so I
think for me it would mean let's go we
at Cisco are ready to tackle that right
we are your partner to help you tackle
any like we're your partner actually at
T helping you to tackle um problems in
your organization we're here to help you
and we're just ready to go like let's go
let's go let's go we're on it and again
this is what Rodney Clark was just
talking about he's our new senior VP of
partner sales um we said it before it's
what he was saying partnership is what
Cisco live is all about in fact I think
Nish mentioned this as well yesterday
February 5th it was partner day here at
the show here at Cisco live and Mia such
an inspiring day it featured all of the
coolest innovations that are driving
partner profitability we heard a lot
about strategic thinking from a lot of
our strategic customers um what we heard
what we'll hear on the keynote what we
heard in the it talk space all of these
different ways that Cisco and our
partners are innovating and growing
together with security and apis and life
cycle management and fulfillment um you
had an opportunity to walk the show
floor a few times I've been stuck right
back here yes but what are you seeing on
the partner front out there and who do
you think is really representing that
partner ecosystem uh who do you look at
and you say there it is that's what I
love to see Cisco doing it's actually a
very good question I think we have loads
of Partners on the on the um in the
world of solutions right surrounded by
Cisco technology so I think what I
explored yesterday is just you know we
have a great partnership with life
nation and they have a really cool Booth
where you can stand and you can become a
rock star and like it has all of these
DSLR cameras and it makes like a 3D
model and it kind of helps to elevate
the VIP experience in like stadiums for
concerts and so on so I think that's
great very very cool and jumping into
the partner part or do we have to go
really quick really quick you've got 10
seconds give me I have 10 seconds okay
great I'm really excited because Oliver
was our previous partner leader I'm just
really excited why he's going to S the
keynote as our new emia leader and I'm
so glad you said it because we're 2 and
1/2 minutes out from that keynote so for
all of you tuning in we're headed to it
first though I'm going to head to Rob
Boyd out on the keynote floor hello Rob
hey Steve how are
you Steve thank you so much we uh have
something here what do you like more
than Champions Cisco Champions and if
we'll just pan over here and have each
of you say your names you're all Cisco
Champions that's the connective thread
here but tell me who you are and what do
you do uh my name is am Nasher I'm based
in U I own a Cisco partner in Saudi
Arabia uh I'm part of Cisco Champions
awesome thank you for that and yourself
she and bom own the three corners and we
do a lot of WebEx and everything
collaboration excellent and Sir with the
cape tell us who you are what do you do
and why the cape well my name is David
penala I'm a Consulting enger for
Verizon business and well I got this
cape as part of the social recognition
and all these what collaboration we do
in the event and why not wearing it why
wouldn't you wear underwear see it fits
so well and it's comfy isn't it no I
love the idea especially when we've had
a little bit of the rainfall outside
it's a little bit of cool I could see
where that would very much be a help but
then I get hot underneath the capes and
I always have trouble finding one that
works with my current outfit but
regardless do you guys come here you've
all been to Cisco live multiple times CU
I've we continue to see each other does
that wrap up or hurry
up send it back got it we're going to go
back to the studio I didn't understand
our hand signals thank you Steve Rob I
appreciate it you always do get hot
under the cape I've always said that
about you and uh yeah you're just
proving it to us here right now we are
headed into our opening keynote of Cisco
live 2024 Amsterdam we're so glad to
have you with us all the different ways
that we can access infinite
possibilities by harnessing that power
of AI we've got Oliver Tuk president of
Cisco imia along with Cisco's technology
leaders they are going to unpack Cisco's
gamechanging technology announcements
all of our innovation they are going to
unveil all of our latest Solutions here
at Cisco and really demonstrate our
commitment to creating a unified
experience for our customers by using
Aid driven capabilities all right so
Cedric as we are ready to head in and
we're going to see the camera shift over
I cut you off a moment ago as you were
walking around the show floor there were
some other innovations that you saw some
of them AI driven give us maybe one or
two more of those before we throw it out
oh that's a good question I think Steve
um I'm always a big big on collaboration
right I think you gave a very good
overview already of what we have in her
portfolio but I just think it's great
how we Empower a hybrid work environment
for customers so I think that's one
where a lot of AI is and the other one I
would call out is that I was at the CX
boot as well and I think you know what
you know we have a whole customer
experience Department to help you
basically Implement all of the
technologies that you basically um
procure from Cisco right and I think we
we cannot forget those guys right and GL
that you brought up CX and I'll just
jump back in because a lot of people
forget that what CX is about is working
together with our customers who have
already made an investment in Cisco to
say you have it it's yours you own it
it's within your infrastructure and your
organization how do you maximize it how
do you take that investment that you've
already made and really grow it to its
biggest and its best potential and
really that's what CX covers for us yeah
absolutely it's it's just they they
bought it right and we are just going to
help them to elevate the organization to
elevate it and oh the wordless solution
is going to open right now something
like that absolutely hey you know what
while this is going on because we don't
want to cover a lot of content with this
let's talk social media all right
because I want to make sure that all of
you who are out here with us on the the
live stream that you continue reaching
out to us and then throughout the
keynote so go ahead and give us those uh
uh social media hits I think the banner
is on screen already but we can engage
with you or you can engage with us using
# Cisco life Amia I'll say that again
because the banner disappeared but #
Cisco life Amia let us know what you
think the keynote it's back in good
thank you so much producer uh so yeah
tell us what you think about the keynote
tell you think uh what you think whether
you're in the room or at home if you're
on the Showcase like just we want to
hear from you right absolutely we are 45
seconds away from heading out to Oliver
Tuk over in the keynote space and again
we want to make sure that you stay with
us all the way throughout not only the
entire keynote but the entire broadcast
we will always be right here waiting for
you in this Cisco TV Studio either me or
Cedric or Nish or Rob or a bunch of us
will be waiting for you right here
between each segment we'll jump between
what we're doing here and also out to
the Innovation talks where there is so
much for you to learn and as Cedric just
said a moment ago on that social media
we want to hear your commentary if you
hear something out in the keynote and
you think there that is what I've been
waiting for that's what I've been
looking for terrific go ahead and post
that up feel free to create some quotes
and put those up send in photos of
wherever you're watching from we're
going to head out to the keynote space
right now we are so excited to have you
with us and excited to hear from Oliver
and the entire team away we go
enjoy please welcome president Cisco
Amir Oliver
[Music]
Tusk good morning and welcome to
Amsterdam the beautiful city of
Amsterdam and welcome to Cisco
life
it's as you you all know this is our
Flagship event and this year it's even
bigger than before with more than 16,000
participants we're fully booked and
these people come from more than 99
countries I hope we still get to the
100 this shows the diversity of the
region that shows the power and we even
have people from the Americas and apjc
so warm welcome to all of you Cisco live
is our event to talk about the news
share the Technology Innovation and to
learn from each other that's why we here
to get better every single day and you
in this event we also utilize the chance
to meet some good old friends and make
some new friends with more than 4,000
first timer here this year and this is
also our chance to say thank you my
chance to say thank you to all the
people that were joining and celebrating
together our success let me start with a
group that is right behind me right now
our press and analysts thanks for
joining us thanks for sharing the news
and special thanks for always being
critical giving us tough feedback and
making us better every single day and of
course all our amazing customers in this
room thanks for being with us it's an
honor to have you and right here we have
the participants of the executive
Symposium I'm looking forward to an
interesting discussion later with you
and not to forget all around the room
all our amazing partners that make us
successful around the world welcome to
all of you but this time I want to give
a special call out to a group of people
they are with our partners they're with
our customers there with Cisco it's a
group of people that make Cisco
technology work they are out there every
day and showing that we deliver the best
results yes I'm talking about our
technical communities all our sees the
software developer the administrators
the Cyber Security Experts we put them
here some of them in the net wet corner
because they're doing it for a long time
it's a personal commitment you put your
career on Cisco we really appreciate it
we will fight hard to deserve this every
single day but with all of you it will
be no problem to continue the journey
nothing can stop us we are ready so
let's go
[Music]
so good to be back in EMA in this region
and as you can see I'm I'm pretty
excited and there's a reason why I'm
excited because I have an advantage I've
been five years abroad living in
California working for Cisco running the
global partner and roots to markets team
and I was talking to customers all
around the world and I also had a rather
outside in to what is going on in Europe
in emia and I can tell you this world
looks much better than we sometimes
thinks because it's not the same place
as when I left it 5 years ago the
digital transformation is accelerating
no matter where we look let's start with
the Middle East where we see all this
Mega projects amazing how they drive
this transformation the speed the power
we've never seen this before for but we
can also go to the heart of Europe to
Madrid where Real Madrid is currently
building one of the best if not the best
soccer stadium ever fully digitized
focused on the best Fan Experience of
course supported by the full Cisco stack
and the next big thing is coming up soon
in Paris Paris Olympics and we are proud
sponsor and we will help them to secure
the games but it's not only there big
events even everybody in talks about
them it's what happening all Industries
no matter where you look all Industries
are driving the transformation and we
will hear from a lot of customers what
is happening we will hear for the
consumer good industry from L'Oreal how
they are driving the changes and we will
hear from many manufacturing companies
down to critical infrastructure Railways
what is happening and we have a great
customer session with
HSBC but they will tell us how they
drive application performance and of
course there's one important group of
customers partners and friends for a
long time our service providers which
are essential and key for driving this
digital transformation and you will hear
from one of them called later what are
they doing and there's one thing we
should not forget is all the great work
that governments are doing across this
region we're working very closely with
all of them with our country
digitization programs to help them drive
this digitization all across the
countries we are
in it's clear technology is key to
manage all this challenge without
technology we wouldn't be able to manage
the challenges we're facing all around
the world but to be also very clear
technology itself is a driver of some of
this disruptions and yes I'm talking
about the biggest disruption ever
AI you will hear a lot about AI not only
how we can help you build the right
infrastructure to run your own Ai and to
utilize the power in a secure way we
will also say tell you how we are
embedding more and more in II in our
products which we're doing by the way
for the last 10 to 12 years but we will
also talk about how we responsible
utilize the power of AI and if you want
to learn more and understand why it's
the biggest disruption ever don't forget
to join me tomorrow in my guest speaker
note with Tom where we talk about what
you need to do and why this is the
biggest disruption
ever now let's be
clear there is something happening when
it comes to it there's an overall
positive momentum it because it is the
one that is changing everything that is
helping to achieve all the targets it's
no longer a cost center only and the job
from all these cios in the rooms has
changed dramatically
not only need to run the daily business
they need to help to drive the business
they need to help to survive all the
surprises and that's a good thing
because we're in a time where it is key
is a
solution I know the GDP growth for this
region is about a percent for this
fiscal year not big but when you look at
the ICT Market the predicted growth for
the ICT Market is four to five times
bigger because companies even invest in
times where they are struggling in their
business because they know they will
only survive and that's the learning
when they utilize the power of
Technology I'm very optimistic as you
can see and I'm bullish and positive for
the future but I'm not stupid I see what
is happening especially in our region we
have two Wars conflicts and a lot of
innocent people are suffering and
there's more no matter where you start
you can talk about energy cost cost of
Liv living global warming instable
political systems and a de globalization
but no matter what is happening we have
an opportunity with it to help and I'm
very proud to see what a lot of you our
customers and partners doing to make
this a more inclusive and a better
place so let me get to the most
important part of Cisco life which is
talking about technology we love
technology there's no no question it's
all about technology for us and being
now more than 10 years with Cisco
approximately 20 years working with
Cisco and being an engineer I can tell
you this is the best portfolio ever it's
more integrated it's more open it's more
automated it's more secure and it's more
AI powered than ever
before is it perfect no of course not it
will take some time to be perfect it
we'll never get there of course but
that's why we're continuously driving
Innovation you will see a lot of this
today and we will also continue to drive
mergers and Acquisitions and the
Acquisitions that we did over the last
year I hope you remember the last big
one about Splunk will be gamechanging
for all of you we will get to a level
where we're getting stronger and
stronger and that's not all we have on
top all our partners that help us to
implement the best Solutions adapted to
your local needs all around the world
when I'm talking with all of my
customers around the world over the last
year I'm hearing always the same topics
what they ask me it's more or less five
to six things it starts always how can
we upgrade the infrastructure how can we
make it ready for AI and the future
world then I'm hearing about how we make
it secure while we're upgrading it and
then again focus on the application
experience how do we create the best
application experience what do I need to
do to empower my users and yes the users
are still living in a hybrid work we
will hear today how we Empower and make
it possible to work in this new world
and of course something that started
here in the Maya we will talk about how
we drive
sustainability and last but not least
the number one question so while I'm
doing all of this how do I drive the
transformation of the company and that's
that's the agenda of today we will cover
all these topics on the main stage and
during all the breakouts and we will
start right away with my first guest
speaker please welcome on stage the EVP
and general networker net general
manager for networking please welcome on
stage Jonathan
[Applause]
Davidson all right thank you so much
Oliver a great entrance I like the walk
again that was fabulous you know so
exciting to be back here today with all
of you and just want to share with you
for years digitalization has ignited our
curiosity about productivity inclusivity
and of course convenience and now ai as
alliver talked about is Fanning those
flames and fueling all of our business
growth and Cisco is absolutely committed
to taking digitalization
and AI even further to help you realize
your
outcomes you know it's been more than 25
years since I made my first IP teleph
call but I still remember the amazement
that it provoked in me it was the
beginning of a new era in communication
and I knew that I was part of something
much bigger than myself now I think many
of you might have felt the same way with
Cloud over the past 10
years and we all know that the network
builds these transformational
Innovations and in return the network is
transformed by these Innovations the
cloud and the network are absolutely
synonymous with each other and I see the
exact same thing with AI there is no AI
without the
network you know it's like driving a
Formula 1
raised car sure all of you know a little
bit about Formula 1
maybe all right so somebody does one
person that's amazing you know you are
in control of something revolutionary as
long as the car is not controlling you
you need to pick crew that can make
split-second
decisions for you Cisco is your crew for
AI think of us as watching the road
ahead for you you can drive while we
give you insights
to avoid threats and anything that is
going to slow you down to do this we are
simplifying and we are securing
networking everywhere for everyone at
every scale that is the Cisco networking
Cloud Cisco networking cloud is an
integrated platform for on premise and
and for cloud operating models it lets
you manage all of the Cisco networking
assets assets and products from one
place fragmented platforms converge
swivel share operations are a thing of
the past hidden threats are surfaced and
eliminated and the platform is powered
by AI to simplify secure and scale your
operations across the entire network
infrastructure now data makes all of
this possible
and one thing I want to share with you
is that Cisco is the internet data
company with visibility into more than
one billion endpoints one billion
endpoints Cisco's data set is orders of
magnitude better than anyone else in
this industry thousand eyes is taking
billions of measurements every single
day across cloud data centers service
providers and of course across
Enterprise networks where you have
enabled that it is able to detect
critical issues and also brownout
conditions so that you can understand
the digital experience of your users
applications and of your things and most
importantly you can take action based
upon that data so let's look at Thousand
eyes in action for branch and for campus
it's given you insights about remote
users their individual devices and the
local area network
and today we are announcing thousand
eyes integration with Cisco secure
access can I get a got a woo from G2
that's great all right that is our
secure Services Edge solution now
security and it have got one place to
see the digital experience of employees
anywhere with secure access you can
immediately see issues across the
endpoint wireless service Prov provider
and all of the
applications how many of you would like
to know that your CIO is having issues
before they do anyone nobody that's
great that's amazing or how would you
like to roll back a change automatically
when thousand eyes sees a problem well
now you can do that and that brings us
down to the individual device with
thousand eyes end point you will see
performance data and you will understand
how you can look at any device and how
that device impacts the applications and
vice versa and that is key for Rapid
issue
resolution no more scattered information
or specialized agents thousand IED
endpoints puts you in control with deep
visibility into specific system
metrics now we also have integrated
thousand eyes into platforms that you
already love like marac
dashboard all right all you need to do
is Select active application monitoring
you then activate thousand eyes on your
MX devices with a few clicks to have
visibility into how the network is
performing for users and for their
applications in fact I did it myself
just last week on my own home network it
was very very easy so let's say that a
site is inaccessible moroi dashboard can
now show you
why path visualization gives you a hop
by hop view of the network traffic
between the MX device and the
destination of that traffic so take a
look thousand eyes found the problem
causing that inaccessible site look at
the red circles user connections are
timing out because a service provider
Network leading to the SAS CRM
application is dropping some traffic now
this is happening multiple hops away out
of the control of it it is causing a
brownout condition and it's owned by
that third party the Enterprise Network
team was able to fix the issue by
routing users around the issue to a
different path this kept the workplace
connected made for happy users and saved
it literally hours of
analysis only thousand eyes can give you
this level of detail we able to
highlight wireless networks identify
realtime issues cross multiple domains
and go deep into third-party SAS
application
performance next up is your journey to
Cloud management and monitoring of all
your Cisco wired and wireless
infrastructure our highest performing
Catalyst switching products are
integrated into the moroi dashboard to
unify and to secure your experience and
The enduser
Experience One one example of Simplicity
with one click you can initiate a remote
packet capture or you can now
troubleshoot with CLI in the moroi
dashboard and now you can see your iOS
XE configuration changes over time
highlighting exactly what changed
between each one of your configuration
versions you can even immediately apply
or you can schedule firmware upgrades
directly from the dashboard in three
clicks for a couple of switches or tens
of thousands of
switches now if you haven't already
started to manage your Catalyst
infrastructure from the cloud we have a
simple secure solution for you the new
Catalyst
9300m can be managed by the moroi
Dashboard directly right out of the box
starting this quarter very excited to
announce you can now monitor your
catalyst 9800 wireless access points and
controllers from the moroi
dashboard I got a woo that's good now
when you're able to see your whole
Access Network you can analyze and you
can fix things so much faster than
before and one company on that journey
is
L'Oreal you know it is L'Oreal has been
a c Cisco customer for so many many
years and now they are embracing this
platform approach and the Cisco
networking cloud and it is beautiful to
see a 100-year-old company embracing
technology to transform let's roll the
video so laal is the largest beauty
company in the world today it is an
enabler for L'Oreal because our Target
is to be the number one Beauty tech
company in the world L'Oreal has its own
research departments factories retail
headquarters and I am responsible for
providing the connectivity and the
networks in all of those locations where
we started 20 odd years ago you know it
was pretty complicated now because of
what we have been able to build and with
the products that we've used we tend to
have high availability Solutions with
the Cisco Mari solution we now talk of
it as being a connectivity platform that
platform is not just the network Wi-Fi
and the wide area network but we have
sensors and CCTV the beauty for us is
that because it's in the dashboard I can
turn off any device anywhere in Europe
from the top of a bus going through
London from my mobile phone that's the
power of having the dashboard and having
the uh app it makes my life really
simple so when the business comes to a
sers to set up a popup in the past it
would take us 2 to 3 months now it's
very much plug andplay automation is
really really important to us at the
very heart of that you have the API and
the API is what enables us to automate
things that we do patching three and a
half thousand devices in 3 days is
fantastic tell me any other device
manufacturer you can do that with doing
things quicker makes it much simpler and
cheaper to do the TC of our Legacy
systems versus our Cisco Mari systems we
reckon is about half if you look over a
5-year period it costs half to run
exactly the same estate as it used to I
keep saying we do more with
less
that's wonderful so now L'Oreal is not
the only company that sees new
possibilities with this dramatic
simplification you might have heard of
company like open AI well both openai
and L'Oreal are rolling moroi out across
their entire Enterprise
infrastructure now we are redefining
cloud-based secure connectivity for the
branch and the campus by integrating the
campus the Catalyst sdwan and the Cisco
secure access our secure Services Edge
solution now this works for branch
internet it also works for SAS traffic
now here you will use the Catalyst sdwan
manager to connect branches to the Cisco
secure access across the sdw fabric then
you can simply apply your security
policy and you're able to deploy it to
Branch sites it is literally that easy
this enables you to rapidly
deploy scalable highly secure sassy
based architectures with just a few
clicks you know the role of it is
expanding Beyond cyber security
customers count on Wi-Fi enabled AI
capable moroi cameras for physical
security one of these customers a
European rail operator uses them to
actually secure their own operations
imagine you're a railway operator with
thousands of cameras running 24 hours a
day you were generating millions of
hours of footage every single
week but how do you make it
meaningful sorting through the footage
to isolate one person or event could
take
days AI is able to solve this problem
within
seconds we can use the moroi vision
portal to filter on objects like
vehicles or people we could even go
deeper with color attributes like
finding the person in the red
shirt now the same customer also uses
moroi cameras to enable rail operations
and rail op and Safeguard restricted
areas the AI has been trained to
recognize employee uniforms and so if
someone goes and enters into a
prohibited designated area without the
uniform the
AI secur security to that
intrusion this all happens without
compromising individual privacy or using
facial recognition and with automatic
video encryption an authenticated
firmware moroi cameras are more secure
against threats but they are more than
simply cameras they are actually sensors
that run machine learning models at the
end Edge for applications Beyond
physical security this is the power of
AI computer vision integrated with the
network powered by the network and
improved by the
network I think there's a camera lover
in the back over there all right with
all the demand for AI powered
applications how do you simplify secure
and scale your data centers and protect
the network
resiliency ethernet and open ethernet
infrastructure delivers fast data
transfers between all of your AI
workloads largescale ethernet-based
Fabrics improve
interoperability job completion time
energy consumption and improves customer
choice and with silicon 1 Nexus and the
Cisco 8000 Cisco is leading the industry
in open
ethernet we have proven this technology
for hyperscalers and used ethernet to
deploy and scale AI as well into the
Enterprise in fact Cisco is the
networker of choice for Enterprise AI
clusters in a brand new Bloomberg survey
66% of Enterprises who use ethernet for
their AI infrastructure are Cisco
customers the next closest ethernet
competitor has
3% now we are announcing that we're
partnering with Nvidia as well as anics
and others to extend this leadership
position and assist all of you we all
know that Nvidia is synonymous with AI
and Cisco is the same with networking
and we're coming together on Enterprise
ethernet networking Solutions we are
putting Nvidia gpus into Cisco servers
and networking Solutions so that you can
design reliable fast scalable
sustainable architectures for AI
workloads inside side of your
Enterprise and then of course we have
our great partnership with
nanx nanic and Cisco have created a
fully integrated and validated hyperon
converge
solution that includes compute
networking and storage across data
centers and clouds nanex also offers
Nvidia
GPU
virtualization all of this simplifies
your infrastructure and enables faster
application delivery and we will
strengthen this relationship even more
by adding new tanx licensing to our EA
buying
programs the Nvidia and the tanx
solutions are each wrapped up in a Cisco
validated design you all know Cisco
designs are endtoend reference
architectures they take the guesswork
out of Designing deploying and
automating data centers to run efficient
AI workloads that helps you both time
and money with cvds you can also choose
container management platforms like red
hat and hypervisors like VMware or new
tanic so that's the Simplicity of our
data center Solutions but what about
scale a large hyperscaler in the US is
in production today with Cisco's
ethernet Network fabric for their AI
workloads in their back-end networks
that's the complicated part it gives
them the power efficiency
it gives them the cost advantage and
programmability to enable them to
compete better in Ai and silicon one is
at the heart of this network AI fabric
this hyperscaler deployed a training
cluster with the configuration that you
see here and that is just the beginning
they plan to deploy this configuration
in many many many more data centers now
if this large hyperscaler trust Cisco to
help them with their AI infrastructure
our Solutions can work for any
Enterprise at any
scale all right for networks that are
connecting Industries economies and
governments Cisco leads the way with the
internet for the
future the internet for the future is
the backbone of digital experiences it's
where Cisco stretches the boundaries of
Technology with secure networks that
scale to Zab capacities and perform at
terabits per
second customers rely on these networks
for five9 availability for those of you
just reminder that's only 5 minutes of
downtime per year our Innovations are
literally changing the DNA of the
internet customers experiences is high
performance low cost and significantly
less internet uh e energy usage take
Colt one of the largest providers in all
of Europe and Cisco is helping Colt and
its customers lead in performance and in
sustainability so look at what happened
when Colt
deployed silicon 1 and routed Optical
networking five nines of service
availability with automation sub 50
millisecond recovery time and all of
their customer services and up to a
97% power savings that is humongous and
coming soon Colt is actually going to be
calculating the power consumption and
the carbon footprint of each one of
their services based Upon Our aidian
solution aidian is able to offer
endtoend service visibility and insights
with microsecond granularity that makes
it faster to launch and monetize SLA
backed services and this is where
automation convergence
scalability and infrastructure all come
together to digitalize the entire world
and this is all accelerated by
AI
the barrier to that promise is
complexity and we're solving that with
the Cisco Network in Cloud complexity is
also the Ally of Bad actors and we're
solving that with the Cisco security
Cloud we all know what it's like to
fight the bad actors The Dread of a
Potential Threat the Panic upon
intrusion the frenzied race to undo any
potential damage what if we could dampen
down that cycle of dread panic and
Frenzy
threats are growing across everything
that connects if it is connected it must
be protected and that unified approach
is driving our strategy for the Cisco
networking cloud and the Cisco security
Cloud together they act as a force
multiplier for simple secure
connectivity and to talk more about that
i' like to invite my friend G2 Patel EVP
and GM of security and collaboration up
on the stage G2
[Music]
great
buddy hello
everyone how's everyone
doing yeah this is there you go that's
what I'm talking about you know I this
is my first time to Cisco live Mia and
what I was told was this is the most fun
loud boisterous audience that I'm going
to ever encounter is that true or is
that not true
okay that that and and is that side is
that true over there
too no not really all right whatever um
well welcome everyone and we we're going
to have a very very um jam-packed set of
announcements and we have some really
exciting news to share with you I'm
going to talk to you about
security uh and this is one of the most
important kind of initiatives that you
see in the world right now and making
sure that the world is safe and so what
I thought I'd do is
walk you through and start with how has
this industry evolved over the course of
the past 30 years or so and if you think
about the security industry over the
past 30 years it's largely evolved with
Innovation through Patchwork and what I
mean by that is every single time
there's a new threat that emerged what
happened was there was a new vendor that
created a product to go out and address
that new threat and consequently what
you've had is about 3,500 or so vendors
in the market each one of those vendors
has a different kind of set of policy
engines on average most organizations
have about 50 to 70 different products
within their cyber security stack and
it's actually frankly untenable to go
out and
manage that level of complexity on an
ongoing basis so it's it's no longer
something that's feasible to continue
down that path right and so um what we
are seeing is this kind of major shift
that's happening in the industry right
now of moving from a bunch of Point
Solutions to integrated
platforms and about 18 months ago or so
we
announced um the um the introduction of
an integrated platform in security
called The Cisco security
Cloud that was uh that largely was built
to solve three key problems one was how
do you protect the
user within the organization how do you
protect cloud and Cloud
infrastructure and how do you protect
against a breach that might happen and
you know very quickly detect a breach if
it occurs respond remediate and recover
from that breach as fast as possible and
all of that was built on a core
Foundation of firewall that's what we
kind of announced 18 months ago and the
team's been really
busy innovating in this area and so
let's talk about what we've actually
delivered to the market so let's start
with user protection and what have we
done in this area of user
protection so one of the big challenges
that you see in user protection is if
you think about a typical knowledge
worker that wants to go out and um you
know connect to any kind of application
so they can get the job done it's
extremely um complicated for that that
individual to go out and just log into
any application because every single
type of application that you log into
you as a user need to know how you're
going to specifically make sure that you
connect to that application so if you
happen to connect to a um you know
private application in your private data
center you're going to have to have a
certain way of connecting to it if you
need to connect to an application that's
a SAS application there's a different
way to connect to it so you might have
you know ztna as one mode of
communication or connection there might
be VPN as another mode of of connection
and it creates a tremendous amount of
cognitive load for the end user as you
just go out and try to get your basic
job done right and we felt like there's
there's a better way that we should
actually be functioning as an
organization so
imagine if it was as simple as you
authenticate to the system and you get
to work you don't have to do a whole lot
else and that's essentially what we
built in this secure access application
that um Jonathan was talking about that
we've integrated completely with
thousand eyes as well and the key over
here is to make sure
that we take care of the plumbing behind
the scenes and all we need to do is
assure that you can make you you can
have the same experience to go un
connect to any application that you
might have private or public whether
you're a contractor or an employee
whether you happen to be at home or at
work it's exactly the same experience
right and so that's what we wanted to do
um authenticate get to work we handle
the plumbing behind the scenes and what
we wanted to do as we built this was
deliver this kind of notion of zero
trust with zero friction and what is
zero trust zero Trust basically says
provide the least privileged
access provide only the amount of rights
that you need to provide to someone so
that they can get the job done rather
than giving them the entirety of access
for everything overprivileged access is
something that's a huge challenge for
most organizations right now so that
essentially is what we've actually built
with the user protection side there's a
tremendous amount of detail make sure
that you go out and see the demos that
might be there and um that are going to
be there the at the booth and the show
floor but it's zero trust with zero
friction now let's jump to Cloud
protection what do you do in Cloud
protection the same notion of zero trust
that's used for users connecting to
Applications we wanted to make sure that
we we had for applications talking to
applications in the data
center so what we did was we said well
let's go out and really look at what's
happening right now in the market and
right now what you're seeing is a
tremendous amount of applications
have actually started moving to the
cloud whether it be on AWS or gcp or
Azure and it turns out that 95% of the
applications that happen to be in the
cloud need to access some sort of
resource in your private data center so
imagine if you happen to be a marketing
application you still need to go out and
access a customer database that might be
in your private data center now how does
this happen today the way that most
people do it is is they actually punch a
hole to the
firewall right and once you've punched a
hole to the firewall you can then have
that application that's running on
AWS connect to an application that
happens to be in your private data
center here's the downside though when
it connects to that customer database it
also gets access to every other
application in that private data center
so it's no longer zero
trust and why is that because typically
what happens is on one side you're
talking IP address right when you when
you think about um the language that's
used in a private data center it's
largely around IP address when you talk
in an application that's moved into the
cloud what's the language you're talking
over there there's no IP address there's
no IP address for Red shift there's no
IP address for Lambda it's just a
service right and those don't talk well
to each other so what we've done is
we've said what if we provided a
translation layer for both of
those so that when that marketing
application wanted to connect to that
customer database we will actually
create a trusted zero trust connection
for that marketing application to
connect to that customer database but
only the customer database not anything
else and that'll work with any of the
firewalls in the industry so if you
happen to have standardized on um a
competitive firewall not Cisco's
firewall that's okay because we'll work
with those as well because we want to
make sure that we are an open integrated
platform right and so that's what that's
basically what we've done now the great
part about this is as you have these
applications that move from one Cloud to
the other let's say that you started an
AWS but you wanted to make sure that you
had a multicloud architecture you wanted
to move it to uh Azure or gcp we can
persist that policy As you move from one
Cloud to the
other so that's essentially what we've
done with Cloud
protection now let's talk about breach
protection what have we done on on the
breach protection side by the way all of
these are capabilities available in
Market in the product today right so
breach protection what do we do with
breach protection
well one of the things that we found was
80% of breaches and attacks that happen
in an organization start from
email there's some kind of funny looking
email that you get from an exotic Prince
from an exotic country that says click
on this link download your $10
million it's burning a hole in our
pocket we want to give it to you you
click on that link it takes you to a
website that didn't exist 2 hours
ago that then downloads some malware on
your device and kickstarts a process and
before you know there's lateral movement
with a new organization that's how
80% of the um of the breaches actually
happen now the challenges in this entire
um you know
domain as I as I talked about earlier
there's 30 3500 vendors there are
vendors that do a really good job
protecting email there are other
companies that do a really good job
protecting the web really um good good
companies that protect endpoint and the
network and what you see is there's a
complete segment kind of you know
isolation of
telemetry because what you see in email
Isn't correlated what's happening on the
web and so what we wanted to do is say
can we correlate this Telemetry to get
better
intelligence right and so how does that
work so what we did was we said if we
actually have the benefit of having
knowledge of every email and every
forward of every request that happens in
the web of every process that gets
initiated on your client and of every
packet that flows through the network
through netf flow data wouldn't it be
great if we could correlate all of these
so a low-level alert that you might have
ignored on an email with a low-level
alert that you might have ignored on a
website with a low-level alert that you
might have ignored because there was
some process that got kickstarted when
you combine them together actually
translates to a high level alert that
you shouldn't be
ignoring and so that's what we did when
we actually launched xdr and this is by
the way the team's done a fantastic job
in this product um they they launched it
a few months ago we've already had a
tremendous amount of momentum with a lot
of customers using it um and make sure
that you go see the demo again but what
we did was we said let's not stop
there because detection is great
and response is great but what you want
to do is go a step further and say what
do you need to do to make sure that you
have some kind of a vaccination against
ransomware you want to make sure that if
something happens and if you are
ransomed you can revert back to where
you used to be right and so we
launched xdr plus recovery with
partnership with some of our client with
some of our partners like cohesity let
me show you how this works this is
actually really cool
all right so this is how it works let's
say that you have a suspicious
process um in um um that's actually
starting now by the way you don't know
if it's known good or known bad because
those are pretty easy to address right
if it's known good Let It Go through if
it's known bad as a process block it the
problem comes in is when it's sitting
right in that gray area what do you do
with that so if you have a suspicious
process that you're not not sure if it's
it's it's sitting in the gray area what
we do now is we can actually immediately
take a snapshot of your envirment M
we're not sure if it's good or bad so we
just going to take a snapshot and then
let's assume that this thing in fact
actually ended up being a piece of
malware um that's going out and
infiltrating your
environment the moment that's starting
to happen we can actually revert back
and go back to a near instantaneous
recovery from the snapshot that we had
taken because snapshots are almost free
to take at this point in time they're so
they were so inex inexpensive that we're
able bble to actually recover back to an
RPO of
zero so what does that exactly you know
kind of mean and what what do you
actually end up doing with this the
beauty about this is um you you're able
to get an
completely um you know kind of uh clear
way of making sure that if there is a
ransomware attack that happened in your
your organization you're able to recover
from that and have a vaccination so that
you you can go back to exactly where the
thing had actually taken over your
environment right and that's all
happening through AI now as many of you
think about xdr many of you might be
thinking well what about Splunk and how
does Splunk play into this as well well
the beauty is Splunk has the log data in
their Sim system we have xdr data but
Splunk has um you know sore data which
is basically orchestrating and
automating an environment and then
you've got user Behavior analytics and
with with Splunk we actually pull all of
these into a single
platform so it's actually uh you know we
can't talk much more about this because
um we are still in the regulatory
process but expect a lot of innovation
between these two things coming together
so that you can be safer as an
organization because you can use that
data and make sure that you actually are
able to take the right level of um
response and Remediation against an that
might might occur within your
organization now as we talk about all
this and as Jonathan went
through what we're doing with AI
infrastructure we also wanted to make
sure that we're innovating in every
layer of AI and so what we've done in
security is we've made AI pervasive
throughout the entirety of the
platform and this is super cool and I'll
show you um what we're doing with the
demo over here in in a moment but
basically what what we're doing is we're
saying there's three things we can do
with
AI in security one is we're going to
make sure that every person who's
managing a security infrastructure has
an
assistant a sidekick someone who can
actually help them um in making sure
that their job is easier so the first
thing that we do is
assist the second area is around
augmenting data with with the human in
the loop and then the third one is fully
automating certain tasks as well right
and so let's talk about what we're doing
over here but what what we did was we
have actually now
launched a Security based assistant and
we were calling it The Cisco AI
assistant for
security it's not a multiple set of
different assistants it's one assistant
that spans all of our security portfolio
for the security Cloud right and so let
me show you a demo of what this looks
like this is super cool you
ready yeah this is a very quiet crowd
are you
ready all right this is a this is a cool
demo I I I I promise you're going to
like it all right
so imagine if you had an interface like
this which is just like chat GPT but for
your security
environment and it's going to ask you
it's basically a prompt interface where
you can just make sure you enter a
prompt so you can just in natural
language enter a prompt that says I need
to update my firewall policy polic What
policies are controlling my sales
application right you enter that in and
immediately what you're going to get
back is a list of here are the policies
controlling access to that sales
application remember this is um we've
actually done this in a completely
multimodal way so you actually enter a
natural language query and you get back
this beautiful kind of table um and and
um and it's a rich media interface you
know kind of back and forth now what
what you do is you say all right fine
that's great add a rule to application
access that blocks outbound traffic from
the sales
app and when you do
that it automatically gives you a
suggestion of what that rule would look
like so I'm setting a rule within my
firewall through a natural language
interface um you know in um in in real
time and you can it'll it'll actually go
out and tell you what the rule is and
it'll ask you whether you want to go out
and implement this rule you hit you hit
yes and voila you've actually gone out
and made sure that that that rule of
blocking outbound traffic from the sales
app has been has been implemented right
away right now what if you say give me a
stepbystep set of instructions on how to
upgrade my
firewall because I don't know how to go
out and upgrade the
firewall what it'll do is it'll give you
a full step-by-step set of instructions
and so what we've done is we've trained
the machine learning model to say what
are the most common tasks that people do
as a firewall administrator and made
sure that all of those are made
available to you through natural
language interfaces how cool is that is
that cool or what this amazing this is
great but we're not done though we're
not done so then we can say all right
this is great but I have a notification
and that notification is around some
kind of policy analysis and optimization
that I'm doing so the AI agent assistant
is smart enough to say hey look you've
got about um 12,34 rules but 353 of
those rules are duplicate
rules so what do you want to do with
those rules you want to delete the
duplicate rules do you want to disable
those duplicate
rules and so the system is providing you
a reasoning engine and it's allowing you
to make sure that not only are you going
out and setting a policy it allows you
to do ongoing hygiene on the policies
that you might have that you weren't
able to do
before right you go ahead and say yes go
ahead and disable those rules or delete
them and it goes ahead and deletes those
rules this by the way is available in
the product
today
right yeah that's
great but we didn't want to stop there
either we said let's keep going so what
we've got is a bunch of new Innovations
in
AI that we're announcing today as well
in addition to that number one we'll
make sure that we can also secure AI one
of the big things that a lot of
organizations are afraid about is my my
data I want to make sure that when it
does go out um into um um into um an AI
model how do I protect it so that the
wrong data doesn't go out so we have
securing AI uh with intellectual
property protection that's going to be
made sure it's part of secure access
that's available today well we also have
is Advanced AI for email threat
detection so you can detect patterns in
email with Advanced AI That's also going
to be that as part of our email email
threat detection and we have ai
assistant for secure uh for Cisco secure
access just like you saw it with
firewall that same assistant is now also
going to be able to allow you to go out
and set policies for your sassy product
and your s product through an AI
assistant
right and this is what it's going to
look like it's that same you know kind
of icon wherever it shows up there's an
AI assistant it's embedded across all of
our
products all right so that's
essentially what we think about when we
think of a Cisco security Cloud
basically what you have is a Cisco
security Cloud that's embedded with AI
everywhere that you go it's in the
fabric of the Cisco security Cloud but
there's one other big problem that we
wanted to make sure that we solved for
which was what typically is the biggest
attack Vector that you're seeing right
now where a lot of breaches are
happening the new attack Vector that
we're seeing is around
identity and identity you know a lot of
people say identity is the new perimeter
in fact
74% of the attacks that are happening
involve a human
element and there's some some kind of
social
engineering that um that's actually part
of that entire kind of process so let's
see how this works because typically
what ends up happening is these
adversaries the threat actors are saying
hey why do I need to hack in if I can
just steal someone's credentials and
simply log in it's a whole lot easier to
do
that
so let's see how this works typically
what you'd have is some kind of a social
engineering
attack where someone would say I'm going
to go out and impersonate a voice
through some deep fake and voice cloning
and call a help desk and make sure that
when I've called The Help test I've had
them essentially reset my MFA password
by the way there is a few high-profile
breaches that happened recently that
happened in a very similar fashion right
and then what you'll see is you added a
new device with that MFA password
research that happened and then all of a
sudden access was
granted um and then everyone the person
got unhindered access into your
system and now they can do whatever they
want to do in the system because they've
actually gone in so the question that
we've all been
asking as we've gone through this entire
um you know kind of past three decades
with identity is can someone does G2
Patel have the ability to log into this
application let's go verify that
typically at the point of time of
authentication once you authenticate
you're in you're free to do whatever you
want and I think it's a wrong question
to be asking the question should
be
should that person have access and can
we assess based on context and behavior
if that person should be continually
granted access it should be a continuous
kind of assessment that's happening and
rather than can they do it we should
find out whether or not they should be
doing it based on the behavior that
they're exuding right and so what we
need to do is fundamentally
reimagine identity based Trust this is
an area there's a huge amount of
innovation possibility and so I'm
delighted to
announce Cisco identity Intelligence
being launched today here in Amia in
Amsterdam
right so let's talk a little bit about
what this does so firstly Cisco identity
intelligence is going to be completely
open it's going to work with any
identity provider that you might have we
don't need to replace any of them it's
going to actually cover the span of not
just human identity but also machine and
service
identity and it's going to be Behavior
aware so the moment you start seeing odd
behavior we're going to make sure that
we can intercept so here's how it
works this is a very typical environment
that most organizations would have
they'd have active directory they've got
some OCTA they've got some Ping Identity
they've got crowd strike they've got
Cisco identity for identity Services
engine you're going to have a lot of
these kind of identity um you know kind
of providers within your organization
what we've done with Cisco identity
intelligence is you provide a thin layer
of analytics on
top of all of those identity providers
and you take all of those identity
providers and utilize that data in that
identity intelligence layer and what we
do is we create an identity
graph now what does this identity graph
do it essentially allows you to
correlate data from humans or users and
devices and applications and correlate
how they all kind of behave with one
another so let's take an example of how
this
works in this identity graph the first
example is let's say that you wanted to
continually assess someone's
Behavior right and so is is G2 doing the
things that G2 is supposed to do so we
can make sure that we give him access on
a continued
basis so if I logged in I would have a
user ID I'd have a certain location I'd
have a role that I'm playing and then
what you would do is immediately let's
say if J2
got uh added to the database
administrators group yeah it's it's a
little odd but not worth actually going
out and stopping anything from happening
he just got added to the database
administrators group but now all of a
sudden I'm starting to show really
peculiar Behavior because I'm starting
to go out and log into
an oracle customer database and start
downloading records or deleting
records what do I do this is when the
identity graph comes in and says okay I
can actually have a graduated response
that seems like anomalous Behavior so
I'm going to make sure that we can kill
that
session right now this isn't just
something that we do from um um reactive
perspective when I'm trying to do
something wrong what about the proactive
side well I've got a bunch of
laptops um that I've actually had maybe
like I've got a bunch of devices that
I've had I've stopped using some of them
because I've got new
devices well wouldn't it be nice if I
can decommission those Legacy devices
and not have them always turned
on the identity graph can tell you which
devices have been um dormant and not
being utilized and actually
automatically to give you an idea of
decommissioning them third example what
happens if you actually want to
eliminate outdated
permissions right let's say that you
actually had some kind of a proof of
concept that you were doing with zenes
and to test out zenes you actually
created a connection between zenes and
Salesforce and then people just forgot
about it they moved on what the graph
will be able to do is tell you well this
connection is not being utilized it's
outdated let's take away the permissions
from
it that's the power of the identity
group ra and that's the power of
actually providing the Cisco identity
intelligence layer and the beauty about
this is we're going to make it available
all throughout Cisco security Cloud now
my ask of
you is to make sure that you can
take a Cisco identity security
assessment which we actually provide to
all of you for
free and what that'll allow you to do is
it'll tell you when MFA is not being
used properly if identity h is not being
practiced in the right way within your
organization and we'll give you a report
this is something if you're interested
in make sure you talk to your account
rep you'll actually be able to go out
and take this identity security
assessment so that you can actually be
safer because you'll know exactly where
the holes are in your system which
aren't
vulnerabilities those are just holes in
your system that someone can log in with
if they were able to go out and
intercept right and so what have we done
here what we've done is basically had an
AI powered Cisco security Cloud
platform and we think identity is so
important and such a huge Threat Vector
for the future that we've embedded that
all into Cisco security Cloud so if you
happen to buy a user protection Suite
guess what identity intelligence is
included if you buy the breach
protection Suite identity intelligence
is
included and the beauty is if you're not
buying the sweets and let's say you're
buying individual applications you're
buying Duo you're buying Cisco secure
access we will make sure that identity
intelligence is also included in one of
the tiers in those products that are
going to be made available right and so
and you will be able to work with any of
the identity providers that you
currently have you don't have to extract
anything you just get this added layer
of intelligence that helps you prevent
against identity threats which is
actually one of the largest concerns
that people have so folks that's
identity intelligence
thank you thank
you
so Jonathan talked about how we're going
to be a great networking
company you can't be a great networking
company if you're also not a great
security company and so hopefully what
you saw over here is we can be a great
security company because of all of this
capability now that's starting to get
built in and the team has hyper
innovated and by the way truth be told I
think we had not innovated for a while
there was there was several years where
our Innovation velocity had gone down
and that is no longer the case we're in
2023 we we innovated more than we had
the 10 years prior and I think you're
going to see an order of magnitude
multiple in 2024 compared to 2023 I'm
really proud of the team and what I want
to talk about next is invite my good
friend ronok so that he can come and
talk about observability Rona come on up
[Applause]
[Music]
all right thank you very much jitu and
I'm going to continue this AI thread and
show you how we are using AI as part of
the
observability you know at Cisco for full
stack observability we're bringing the
network Insight security insights and
application intelligence all together to
help you deliver that Flawless and
secure digital experience for everyone
every
time one year ago we stood here in front
of you and laid out our full stack
observ
strategy and I'm so happy and proud of
our team who helped us delivered every
solution and use case which we talked
about you know digital experience has
has become a keyboard room
metric Cisco app Dynamics and Cisco
observability platform is helping you
achieve your observability
goal as part of my role I meet a lot of
you and you told me loud and clear that
you want a unified and a simple
observability
experience in fact you told me that you
have many many monitoring tools
somewhere between 10 to
140 monitoring tools clearly this is
causing High total cost of
ownership causing frictions amongst your
op steams but more importantly it's
delaying your resolution and time to
detect so our use case driven approach
for full stack observability is really
resonating with our customers as you can
see the way we do that is by unifying
the data hence reducing the frictions
between your op steams improving the
operational efficiency at the same time
reducing the business
risk and in fact Gartner agrees with
us they recognized us as customer's
Choice peer insight for observability in
2023 we talked about lot of use cases
and when I see the demo of that it just
giv gives me a pure joy and opportunity
for you all to see that live on the show
floor but here are the four use cases
which I really want to kind of spend
time today the first one is around sap
monitoring you all know sap users really
want to understand bottleneck into their
sap
transactions they want to be predictive
and proactive and more importantly they
want to do a quick root cause analysis
so that they can avoid the
outages you know one minute of outage on
sap lscape can cost you tens of
thousands of
dollars so just think about it few hour
of outage what it can do to your brand
and
yourself so let us help you reduce that
pain the Second Use case is around
business risk
observability you know security risk
assessments are top of the the mind for
our security Ops it Ops and application
tram and I'm very happy to announce
extension to our business risk
observability with dspm observability
which is data security posture
management observability this is helping
you detect discover analyze and quickly
take action to protect your data and
protect your
brown the third use case is around
digital experience monitoring
to deliver that Flawless digital
experience you really need to understand
every component your application depends
upon and we at Cisco have a unique
Advantage where we can provide you that
end to end holistic understanding of
that application
dependency by ingesting Network Insight
from thousand eyes and private Insight
from expedience we are able to give you
those critical vantage point points
allowing you that visibility and insight
to help you deliver that Flawless
digital
experience and I am very happy to
announce we are extending the digital
experience monitoring by adding session
replay as part of that and it is going
GA this
week it's like Netflix you have access
to millions of users who are accessing
your
application but we have simplified by
building in Analytics so that we can
quickly narrow down the problematic
sessions and it is that simple please do
go experience that for yourself on the
demo
floor you we know pressure on you and
your it team is higher than
ever so this week Cisco AI Ops is going
live this is providing you actionable
insights to help you improve your it
operation reducing your meantime to
detect and repair by focusing on
correlated fals and insight we're
helping you and your team to streamline
The Incident Management and change
management you ask for it and we are
delivering
it monitoring llm usage by your
applications from a cost perspective and
API perspective is already
available and we are adding natural
language interface on our query language
this is like interacting in a human
natural language with our
tools and I'm very happy to announce
that we are going to add autonomous root
cause analysis with Cisco AI assistant
for
observability Cisco observability
platform is unique from a perspective of
it's open it's API driven and it's
extensible and it's that power of
extensibility which allows our partner
to do the rapid Innovation on this
platform and I happy to announce eight
new partner modules starting from
business inside mlops to
SLO just to put it in a
perspective our partners have delivered
24 modules since the time this plantform
went
G that's a module a
week and this rapid pace of innovation
is possible because of the power of
platform you've heard a lot from me and
I know observability is the top of the
mind for you all so I want to Welcome to
the stage P managing director at HSBC
she's got a great vision for full stock
observability and she is benefited by
our partnership and some of the
solutions which we are talking about it
so welcome pek to the
[Music]
stage
pek thank you very much for joining us
here thank you thanks for having me pek
recently your CEO publicly shared that a
key part of hsbc's strategy is to invest
in digitization and
Technology this is a huge opportunity
and also a big challenge what is it how
does this represent for you and your
teams first of all thanks for having me
here Rach indeed at hspc we're really
embracing the digital world as people
are leading increasingly digital lives
we are putting the full power of our
bank in every customer's pocket with
easier and more secure digital banking
in simple terms we're putting our bank
in your pocket vision 27 uh is our
long-term technology strategy is helping
to transform
HSBC to into a digital First Bank while
we are demising Legacy and non-strategic
applications as part of our efforts to
really streamline what is a very large
and complex technology
architecture now digitize at scale with
growing dependency on third party
Services means increasing complexity in
our environments but it also means
increasing number of changes that is
delivered into our production Network
only last year we delivered more than
800,000 changes
there is 19% up from the previous year
and if we continue with this trend we I
think can comfortable to say that we can
easily exit the 1 million mark this year
so ronak as we're transforming HSBC into
a digital bank at PACE we at Tech in
technology what we must really do is
have a very sharp focus in protecting
our production and that is only possible
by uplifting our technology resilience
which also includes investing in
observability and AI ops Oh that's was
not me yeah we know the banks role in
this global economy yeah so security and
up time I'm sure is not
negotiable so what does technology
resilience means to HSBC how do you
approach it specifically in context of
observability you're absolutely spot on
resilience is not negotiable so as a
bank our life Li to operate very much
rest on trust trust of our customers
Trust of our staff Trust of our
regulators and public as a whole and I
assure you we take this responsibility
very very seriously and that is why we
are taking a very proactive approach to
technology
resilience at HSBC as part of our vision
27 technology strategy we developed a
very powerful and very unique tool for
our industry
this is a self assessment tool called
technology resilience maturity framework
trmf for short we use trmf to assess and
categorize our resiliency maturity
levels across our technology stack as
well as our third party partners and we
use this to determine our resiliency
uplet requirements now what is really
cool about this tool and very great for
our colleagues is it provides a Common
Language between the business and the
technology colleagues so that they
actually have a Common Language they can
understand and they also use this to
make priority calls for the Investments
they make in order to uplift our
resilience now trmf uses multiple type
of criterias as you can imagine it's
quite a a comprehensive capability But
it includes criterias around
observability it is obser observability
that is important because as you were
pointing out earlier as well is that
observability gives us a way to identify
anomalies uh identify probably
previously unknown Falls or problem
areas it allows us to proactively uh
prevent incidents if not detect and
restore incidents much faster but also
it gives us the insights to much better
more accurate ways to identify root
cause for any incidents as well so in
business terms for HSBC what does this
consistent and unified approach to
observably mean to you your teams and to
all our customers here yes so first of
all observable C must ensure the
technology teams are more aligned and
more focused on customer
outcomes therefore it should really
closely tied into the service defined
service level objectives now over many
years we have made significant progress
uplifting our monitoring alerting and
logging capabilities by introduction of
tools like app Dynamics T eyes spun and
many other of course this helped us to
deal with the complexity of the
environment uh to some extent but what
we're focusing on right now is to really
build this end to end unified
observability as you said earlier across
all components within an IT ser service
chain so that we have a better
visibility to the health state of our
important business services and we aim
to do this consistently across
technology
globally we also are looking to
integrate observability capabilities
with our trmf tool because that will
give us a live view of our resiliency
posture which will of course strengthen
our approach to risk management across
the bank thank you very much pek and I
know we can spend an hour talking about
it but don't worry we're going to spend
more time at noon in my ey talk between
pek and I there's a QR code up here to
see the announcements which we're making
it this week uh but to uh talk about
hybrid work I want to welcome my dear
friend jitu Patel on the stage thank you
very
[Applause]
[Music]
much all right you thought you'd get rid
of me you're not getting rid of me that
easy so we're going to talk about two
more very important board initiatives
one of them is fundamentally around
hybrid work how are people working
what's the future of work going to look
like and the second is around customer
experience how do we make sure that we
fundamentally create better brand
loyalty when a customer has an issue
with the brand that they're engaging
with so let's start with um you know
talking about hybrid work and then you
know there's two specific areas in
hybrid work that we actually are focused
on one is fundamentally reimagining
workspaces people work from everywhere
we need to make sure that we actually
reimagine the workspaces and what how
they're going to use that that property
in the way today compared to the way
that they used to use it 10 years ago um
and one of the key areas that's actually
fascinating is
98% of meetings that you'll see in the
future will have at least one
participant that's going to be not in
the same physical location as everyone
else 98% of the meetings right but only
a
third of the conference rooms in the
world are actually video
enabled and so as we thought about this
we said what do we do one of the things
that we wanted to do was fundamentally
take away the distance between two
parties when they're not in the same
physical space as everyone else right
and so this notion of distance zero is a
big kind of principle for us as we think
about innovating in this new world of
hybrid work
and so how do you get to distance zero
what are the things that we do well one
of the things that we're doing is it's
not just about putting a video and a
screen on every room it's actually much
more than that we have to fundamentally
make sure that we architect the room in
such a way that it takes away the
distance and so we've provided
blueprints for every different kind of
room to our customers whether it be a
boardroom huddle space theater style
rooms conference rooms to make sure that
there's a level of
distance that can be taken away and
people feel like they're immersed and
right there with each other in fact one
of the most magical things that we've
actually seen happen at Cisco uh and
with a lot of our customers is sometimes
you don't even remember if you've met
someone in person or not because the
distance is taken away in the way in
which you engage with them and the way
that this happens is we've actually got
a complete portfolio of devices that we
built for every single
space that um that we want to equip with
this kind of notion of distance zero and
there's a couple things that have really
been fascinating as we've innovated in
the devices because we completely
changed our mindset a few years ago
where we said well rather than just
having devices that work with only the
WebEx platform why don't we have devices
that work with any platform that
customers are
using and so we have completely opened
up our devices so that you can actually
have it work with zoom you can have it
work with Google and we've actually made
a special partnership with Microsoft
where Microsoft team rooms can run
natively on our
devices and when Microsoft team rooms
runs natively on our devices WebEx can
be another application that runs there
so that's the first big change that
we've had which is you've we' made sure
that we made it open the second big
change was a decision that we made about
five or six years
ago which was around making sure that
every one of our devices would have an
Nvidia chipset in it
so that we could actually pack it with
capabilities for
AI and now that's actually really
proving out to be extremely valuable
because we have ai capabilities that are
not just in our devices but those
capabilities for AI can make every other
platform that integrates with our
devices better so if you actually use
Microsoft teams they will get benefit of
noise removal and noise cancellation and
video intelligence because that's
something that's baked into the devices
now it's not just about collaboration
and hybrid work we want to make sure
that we actually take the power of the
entirety of the portfolio of Cisco so
what we also have is this ability to
deliver workspace optimization through
Cisco spaces and they can take Telemetry
from moroi um Wi-Fi access points and um
uh iot devices and all of those pieces
and give you a schematic of exactly what
your space looks like what space are
available and it also takes the
Telemetry from the devices right and so
that's reimagining workspaces themselves
everything from how you kind of walk
into a space to how you actually might
engage with people when you're in the
space we also wanted to make sure that
we fundamentally reimagine
work and when you think about
reimagining work one of the things we
wanted to do was make sure that
everything that we had had a similar
kind of experience and was built on a
platform so a few years ago the WebEx
platform actually delivered the WebEx
Suite which includes calling messaging
meetings polling Q&A events
whiteboarding async video all of those
things for the price less than the cost
of
Netflix right and you have that
capability with a single platform where
you actually make the Innovation once
and it's actually available in every
single application that we have in the
platform and it all looks and feels the
same it's all full fully integrated it's
a gorgeous UI and so that's something
that we've actually worked really hard
and it was completely secure now this
mentality of making sure that we have
something that's frictionless as an
experience honoring people's
privacy and keeping organizations safe
is a core principle that not only do we
care a lot about and ourcustomers care a
lot about but there's another partner
that actually shares those same values
just as much as we do and that's
apple right and so apple and Cisco
together um are fundamentally better
together and so what we've done is we've
said how can we make sure that we
continue to keep working closely with
apple everything from the way in which
our Network integrated with apple to um
what we've done with our mobile devices
and so on and so forth but then there
was this kind of magical moment that
happened earlier this
year where they la launched I think one
of the most consequential devices of our
times and that's the Apple Vision
Pro and let's take a look at what we've
done with
that enter the era of spatial Computing
WebEx for Apple Vision
Pro for every space is your favorite
workspace with an infinite canvas that
lets you drag and drop as you
collaborate leveraging industry-leading
features like realtime translation and
AI noise removal in a whole new
experience this is WebEx for Apple
Vision
[Music]
Pro available in the app store
today right and the beauty about this is
it's also a featured app we're so
excited to work with apple in fact we
have some of our friends from Apple that
are here thank you for the partnership
and um just know that we will continue
to keep investing in the part
partnership and we'll continue to keep
investing in building amazing products
that actually have privacy at the front
and center security at the front end
Center and a beautiful experience that
you just feel like um you've completely
immersed into it so that's um Apple
now how do you also make sure that you
don't just reimagine workspaces and work
but also customer
experience and for imagining customer
experience one of the things we did was
we said let's utilize that same
platform that we've used for video and
audio um for WebEx and make sure that we
can have a worldclass customer
experience set of applications built on
top of that right and so with that core
WebEx platform what we've done is we've
delivered a great way that you can not
only do customer experience where when
someone calls you have the right kind of
software to go out and give them a great
experience but we start with proactive
Communications but sometimes the
customer shouldn't even have to call
because something's gone wrong and you
as a brand can proactively make sure
that you take care of that customer we
also want to make sure that we can
provide every customer the ability to
selfs serve if they wanted
to but there is such a thing as wanting
to have the desire to talk to a human
from time to time and when they do we
want to make sure that you don't have to
keep repeating yourself you don't have
to keep feeling frustrated and you can
actually talk to that human and get your
problem solved as easily as possible and
you might start the communication with
that brand on a website in chat and then
you might decide to jump on a voice call
and we will actually keep complete
context of that and all of those
multiple channels whether it be WhatsApp
or websites or Instagram uh or a
telephone call or a video call will all
actually maintain context and so that
you don't have to repeat yourself over
and over again right and the beauty
about this is we've actually made these
Solutions available for everyone so we
used to have um a standard and premium
version which was a feature contact
center and then recently we announced a
contact center
basic so that you could actually have
smaller more tactical teams that might
not need a very heavyduty contact center
also be able to benefit from it and
that's included in the WebEx
Suite right and so in the WebEx Suite
when you buy the WebEx Suite you'll
actually get that basic contact center
you might have multi-line communication
or you might you might have a a few set
of features that even your it help desk
or your HR ticketing system might
actually need from time to time when
there's a surge and so that's that's
available and then what we've done is
we've said let's take it a step
further and so what we're announcing
over here is the essentials version
which is actually something that's going
to be made available for a much lower
price than the full-fed standard version
for $30 um you know per user per month
and what that's going to have is the
ability for having any individual within
your organization that can actually
participate in helping solve problems
for customers not just the contact
center
agents and so you have a lower price
point you're able to go out and get
there and all of this is built on a core
fabric of AI and AI is as just like what
you saw in
security AI is pervasive throughout the
entirety of the
platform and
so what we did was we said let's make
sure that we have once again a unified
AI
assistant for all of the properties of
WebEx right and so whether it be the
WebEx Suite or it be Cisco devices or
WebEx control hub for going out and
administering and managing your console
um you will have a single AI
assistant and essentially that AI
assistant is going to be called a Cisco
AI assistant for the WebEx Suite let me
show you a quick demo that's going to
blow your
mind this is very cool all right so the
scenario over here is I'm sitting in a
meeting and all of a sudden the doorbell
rings because I buy a lot of crap online
at night right and so doorbell rings and
I have to make sure that I get up so
Clarissa is like me she gets up the
system automatically knows Clarissa
stepped away she blurs the camera and
she's um you know um it's um she people
have detected she's gone she's gone away
the moment she comes back she's going to
be asked hey do you want to catch up on
the 3 minutes of the conversation that
you missed so you can recap that
conversation for you from the time that
you stepped away to the time that you
came back so that you don't have to go
out and distract anyone else in the
meeting how cool is
that
right and the same summarization
capability is also available on our
messaging platform it's also available
in vidcast in the entire entirety of The
Suite the beauty about this is when you
get a transcript at the end of the
summary you will even know in the
transcript on what transpired besides
just the um um just the script so you
might see the transcript the transcript
will have Clarissa stepped away there
was an emoji there were people that
applauded all of those non-verbal cues
will actually be something that'll be
available in the transcript for you so
you can see what might have you know
kind of transpired so we're really
excited about all of these capabilities
for AI you should expect these to be at
a very high velocity of innovation
that'll continue to keep getting
launched and delivered to you um and um
this is what that transcript would look
like now it's not just for the end user
we also care about the it administrator
making their lives easier with AI so
what have we done over there we've said
how do we make sure
that everyone who's an IT administrator
we make their experience magical with AI
so what we've done is basically
brought everything together for it by
making sure that we have a common data
Lake platform on top of that we have an
analytics platform and then WebEx Suite
WebEx Cisco devices as well as the WebEx
contact center are all managed in
one single administrative management
plane
which is called the WebEx control Hub
right and this is not just something
that I believe is one of the best in the
collaboration industry I think in
Enterprise software it's going to be
hard to find amazing management tools
like the like control Hub and so what
you see over here is an example of
control Hub and what we've done is not
only made sure that you can have
everything managed from the single um
location we've also now integrated that
with network performance insights with
moroi so right from within control Hub
you can actually have an integration
into moroi and then we said let's take
it a step further and that step further
is providing the Cisco AI assistant for
control Hub so what does that do exactly
what would you do with the Cisco AI
assistant for control Hub let's say that
you actually had um word from someone as
an IT administrator that this um senior
executive Donna Miller in your
organization um has actually been having
some bad quality issues for some reason
what you can do is you can just simply
ask the AI assistant hey uh how is Don
Miller's quality of the experience that
she's having show me any issues that
she's having and it'll actually tell you
that during a meeting Donna
Miller had some choppy audio but it's
actually going to take it a step further
it's going to show you
exactly where that choppy audio is if
you wanted to see the detail
and then if you said why did she get
that choppy
audio we'd integrate that with thousand
eyes so thousand eyes is then going to
be able to provide you with details on
how the network path is actually going
to show you why that actually why that
issue occurred so in this particular
case it was a local ISP that caused the
issue sometimes it could be the app
sometimes it could be uh your device
sometimes it could be the network we'll
actually be able to pinpoint exactly
where that issue is for the network
administrator and the beauty about all
of this is I'm asking questions in
natural language and I'm getting back
responses in
charts another big area that we actually
focused
on is
sustainability and what we're going to
do with control Hub is make sure that we
actually add more capabilities for
sustainability inside control Hub as
well so today we are announcing a new
low carbon mode for
sustainability so folks that's the
entirety of the collaboration platform
tremendous amount of innovation in both
in all the areas of our business from
networking to security to observability
to collaboration we're so excited and
thrilled to bring all of this capability
to you and with that I'm going to hand
it back to my good friend
Oliver
thanks a lot thanks a lot G2 and all the
speakers I hope you know understand why
I believe it's the best portfolio ever
we covered most of the question that I
brought up at the beginning but we
haven't talked about one very important
topic and that's the topic of
sustainability yes we have great
technology as you just heard to support
you but this is not an easy project to
get it started but we got somebody to
help you
we have a team of more than 6,000
service people experts that are working
together with our partners to help you
and it's now up to my dear colleague
Adele trombeta who's running customer
experience the service teams all around
the Mia to explain you how she can help
you
rocket hello hello everyone it's great
to be here with you all so now topic is
sustainability you have heard a lot
about that but the point is where do we
start how do we start well we start with
an
x-ray I know it may sound strange but
before x-ray what happened underneath
the human body was invisible to The
Naked Eyes with x-ray suddenly invisible
became visible and this is exactly how
we should manage
sustainability why because not everybody
has visibility into their sustainability
performance actually we have done a
study with IDC and we found that only
18% of the IT department in AA they have
defined their sustainability Base Line
Target and they regularly track them but
you need visibility to be able to act
and that's even more important in light
of the recent EU uh init iives with
strict sustainability
goals and we can help you now when you
run an x-ray you may found some
challenges you may lack tools automation
data Foundation to get the right Insight
or you may need help to use technology
in order to continue evolve your
business performance while helping your
sustainability goals or you may you may
struggle with your budget if you are not
able able to quantify the impact of your
sustainability
initiatives but consider that
91% of the Serv business in M that saw
profitable growth from daily
sustainability initiatives they Align
Technology and sustainability goals so
sustainability is great for business too
and what make the difference is how we
use the
technology now I'm deeply passionate
about sustainability and equally
passionate about your success I want
each of you to achieve profitable growth
and your sustainability goals and with
the power of the technology of Cisco
technology silicon 1 AI full St
observability and the amazing expert
sustainability expert we can help
imagine your data center with 40% less
power capacity and 23% less operational
cost or your offices with 50% less power
consumption and cost while improving
your employee experience and if you
belong to the digit to the utility
sectors well we are digitizing the grid
across most of the European
countries these are real and proven
savings we have done that without our
partners and we are ready to do that for
each and everybody of
you now the big question is how do you
do that well there is no one Jour fits
all why because you are unique your
technology footprint is unique and so
will be your sustainability
Journey but three steps can help each of
you the first is shape we can run an
x-ray with our maturity assessment
framework to gain
visibility to align your sustainability
and Technology goal and in in third we
can build an actionable road
map second step is scale we can bring
together the global expertise experience
Solutions in order to First improve your
energy consumption with real time
observability digitize your workplace
and automate the most critical processes
in many Industries last is sustain you
have to sustain your journey and to do
that we have built amazing and digital
dashboards that will give you real time
data insight and
recommendations now you have heard a lot
from me why don't we hear from our
customers
please run the
video automation will deliver better
customer experiences operational
efficiencies and help us to achieve our
Net Zero Energy goals within Vision 27
now we're working together with Cisco to
drive this transformation with a greater
purpose we are working with Cisco on our
sustainability strategy for our global
data centers with their expertise we
will reduce our carbon footprint more
importantly increase our usage of
renewable energy working with CX has
been important to make the concept of
smart buildings repeatable and
sustainable we're looking at over 70%
less electricity to run 10x worth of
performance and that's better for
sustainability it's better for our
costs Cisco's part of Expos family it
was a fusion of shared values and
expertise demonstrating our agility and
commitment to a sustainable
solution
well
Oliver these customers are amazing
sustainability change makers and every
year at Cisco live talking about change
makers we celebrate the CX customer
Heroes they are all with us today so
please join me in congratulating Yer
Peter Sandra Fatima Eman PK and
Anders
great
job it's great to see how many customers
adopting this and I hope the matches
watch clear together with our partners
we're ready to help you on the
sustainability Journey but this is only
a small part of your job uh we don't
have a lot of time but there's a lot of
other stuff going on just tell the
people what's happening what's new
what's available absolutely right
improving sustainability is just one of
the outcomes we can help you with and if
you need to reduce your cost or enhance
your security or improve your compliance
or any of the other business outcomes we
can help you with our life cycle
services with more than 6,000 experts in
my team and tens of thousand expert with
our partners we have got your back and
we are ready to start let's go thanks a
lot
Adele
so
we started talking about customers and I
want to end this session with a customer
close to me and we love all customers
but this is a special one it's a very
special one for us at Cisco and you will
understand in a second why he's a
special one please welcome on stage
Cisco's CIO Fletcher
[Applause]
prevan
[Music]
so it's good also to have you on stage
finally thanks for having me so of
course I will ask you a couple of
question how are you looking at what we
are telling our customers because people
might not know you're always our
customer zero you need to test whatever
new idea we came up with and you don't
have a lot of options I believe but
let's start with AI because because I
remember there was a time where we
decided we build up an AI INF structure
share the experience how this was yeah
thanks well so as the name implies when
you're customer zero that means there
are zero people who have done it before
and we get to find ourselves doing a lot
of things for the first time which is
the challenge and the excitement and so
we needed to build a high performance AI
cluster of gpus using Cisco ethernet
stack and be able to prove that we could
do that that uh and along the way create
shared infrastructure that can be used
all across the company and also create a
blueprint that other people can reuse
and then uh use RDMA to prove that
there's no loss in between the gpus and
the cluster and so that's exactly what
we were able to do you can see here the
diagram of it you've got the uh the 400
gig uh leaf and spine where there are 32
nodes and 256 Nvidia h100 gpus each of
those gpus are directly connected by a
400 gig Optical uh into the 100 Gig
storage Network the 100 Gig uh inband
network uh the control plane and then
off to the right you've got the 10 gig
connectivity uh for the out-of band
management which is you know probably a
little over-provisioned for out of band
but hey I work at Cisco so if anybody
gets to over-provision it's me and uh
ISR is for out of band and uh cat 9
Nexus 9ks and Cisco 8000s as the
ethernet uh backbone of it and so we
this is real we have built this uh in
fact I think we have a picture of the uh
the just to prove that it's real look at
all that beautiful cabling and and fiber
uh I obviously did not cable this or it
would look very different but um this is
up and running people are using it and
along the way we've made a a blueprint
that others can reuse which is important
thing this one didn't look as nice as
the picture that Jonathon was showing
but this is real it's up and running and
we can help you with building the
blueprint so this is mean we're running
all our AI stuff on this one which means
everybody can use AI in the company so
we can use cat GPT and all the other
models we have made cat GPT uh co-pilot
uh available to all employees in the
company although we've done it in a way
where it's running in a uh private
tenant so that we can control and log
and audit all of the pr s that are put
into it none of that data leaves the
corporate Network none of that data is
ever used as Public Training data uh
it's done in a safe and secure
way um and uh you know that's allowing
us then to take things like the power of
an llm combine it with techniques like
uh retrieval augmented generation and
use some of our proprietary information
to really add value and have people be
able to use AI against some of the
proprietary information that things like
product information and and case notes
from the TAC and things like that
perfect now one more question because
everybody is not only talking about
building up but using it and are you
using within your team AI to be more
productive faster better yeah for sure
we are taking advantage of the
productivity benefits of things like Ai
and the WebEx Suite AI Ops and things
like Catalyst center that is making it
possible for us to uh take things that
we would maybe typically do like once
every couple of months like attenuate
the radios on the wireless access points
and automate that to be something that's
happening every 30 seconds by
itself so let's jump to the next Hot
Topic sustainability M um everybody got
big commitments and we made a big
statement what we going to deliver so
did you get an extra budget to deliver
on this one uh I I did not get an extra
budget to deliver this no so so the same
as most of you are face but I assume
it's still expected that you
deliver yeah I mean uh apart from that
just being important for the planet and
the right thing to do there are very
practical reasons why as the IT
department we have to aggressively get
after that if you think about typically
in a data center historically we would
provision maybe 5 to 10 kilow of power
per 42u rack uh something like a high
performance AI GPU cluster we need maybe
60 to 70 Kow of power power per rack so
in order to be able to build the AI
infrastructure that we're all going to
have to build within the envelope of of
what we have in our data center we have
to get as efficient as possible and save
as much power as possible everywhere
else from the top of rack down so uh yes
it is something we're we're uh but you
need so you need to do it anyhow because
otherwise you would not be able to
manage energy cost and energy capacity
exactly great now as I said you're
customer zero and you're special
customer zero because I assume you're
not allowed to buy anything else in
Cisco correct well why would I need to
buy anything else it doesn't even occur
to me to buy anything else okay so then
let ask me how do you get the benefit
out of the entire Cisco portfolio what
is your advice to all the cios the it
leader in the room yeah well you know if
I think about um like a complex endtoend
problem like hybrid work and you think
about really all of the problems that
need to be addressed with that from
remote access survivable connectivity
device management productivity cyber
security
sdw um uh
observability you know you heard
Jonathan talk about the value of the
platform and G2 talk about how
fragmented some of these spaces
are that's a lot of complexity where if
I don't have to be the integrator of
dozens of different Niche Point
Solutions and I can just take advantage
of the entire integrated
platform that's saving me complexity and
making the IT job a lot
simpler perfect I think there's nothing
more to add on such a summary driving
the complexity down with a portfolio
that goes end to end fer thanks for
being with us it was a great pleasure to
have a CIO with me on the end thanks to
all of you for joining us the show will
continue and I'm looking forward to
seeing you all tomorrow have a great day
thanks a lot
brother